SOFTWARE ENGINEER



abbasquliyev111@gmail.com https://github.com/abbasquliyev https://www.linkedin.com/in/abbas-guliyev/

Profile Summary

I am a software developer mainly focused on backend development using Python. I have a clear and logical mind with a practical approach to a problem-solving. I have a solid experience in building backend applications with Python. I also have strong analytical skills - experience in modelling entities and creating API to satisfy business requirements.

Professional Skill

- Python
- Django
- FastAPIRedis
- Pydantic
- React
- Djange
- Graphql
- Sqlalchemy
- Django Rest Framework
- PostgreSQL/MySQL
- HTML/CSS/Bootstrap
- Git

- Django Channels
- Celery
- Javascript
- Docker

Education

Bachelor - Metallurgical Engineering

2015-2019

Azerbaijan Technical University

Work Experience

Fullstack Developer

April 2023 - Current

VESNAT Technology | Remote

- Develop web applications using Python/Django and React
- Provide support for applications

Backend Developer

October 2021 - April 2023

Kodaze | Baku, Azerbaijan

- Develop backend of web applications using Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, PostgreSQL, Celery, Redis, Graphql.
- Provide support for applications

Python Teacher

November 2021 - July 2022

ITEM Academy | Baku, Azerbaijan

• ITEM Academy is an organization that organizes free courses and seminars for students in many fields in Azerbaijan. I volunteered to teach a python based full stack programming course here. I had 10 students. I taught python, django, django rest framework, html, css, bootstrap, javascript, postgresql, mysql for 9 months.

Python Developer

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

ITEM | Baku, Azerbaijan

- Develop web applications using Python/Django.
- Provide support for applications.

Language

AzerbaijaniEnglishTurkish